Finding Aid for the Jonathan Friedlander Collection of Middle Eastern Americana LSC.1314
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Sound Recordings, 1950 - 2005; 5 oversize boxes
  - Phonograph records, 1950 - 2003; 5 oversize boxes
    - Music from the motion picture the Bible, The ten commandments, The greatest story ever told, King of kings, Ben-Hur New York, NY: MGM., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Music from the motion picture the Bible, The ten commandments, The greatest story ever told, King of kings, Ben-Hur New York, NY: MGM., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Creator: Newman, Alfred
    - Music from the motion picture the Bible, The ten commandments, The greatest story ever told, King of kings, Ben-Hur New York, NY: MGM., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Music from the NBC-TV film Holocaust New York, NY: RCA Red Seal., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Creator: Gould, Morton, 1913-
      Cover illustration by Paul Davis.
    - Music from the NBC-TV film Holocaust New York, NY: RCA Red Seal., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Creator: Davis, Paul
    - Music from the soundtrack of Cecil B. DeMille's The ten commandments New York, NY: Paramount., 1956; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Cover is a photo of Charlton Heston as Abraham. Includes images from motion picture.
    - Oke no monsho Japan: Canym Records., 1982; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Translation: Imperial family crest. Features illustration of pharaoh and pyramids.
    - Original theme from the movie Cleopatra and mystic melodies of the Nile New York, NY: Palace., 1964; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Creator: Viennese Symphonic Orchestra
      Cover features sketches of Cleopatra, the Sphinx, and the pyramids.
    - Original theme from the movie Cleopatra and mystic melodies of the Nile New York, NY: Palace., 1964; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Original theme from the movie Cleopatra and mystic melodies of the Nile New York, NY: Palace., 1964; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Creator: Ewing, Bill
    - Original theme from the movie Lawrence of Arabia New York, NY: Palace., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Creator: Alexander Maloof Orchestra
      Cover is a photograph of Peter O'Toole posed as T.E. Lawrence. Jacket excerpt reads, "This album will capture for you the mood and spirit of Lawrence of Arabia, the pageantry of desert warfare, the movement of 100 camels, the solitude of shifting desert sands, and the magic of the Oriental influence of the people."
    - Original theme from the movie Lawrence of Arabia New York, NY: Palace., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Pharoahization! The best of Sam the Sham and the Pharaohs Santa Monica, CA: Rhino Records., 1965; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Creator: Samudio, Domingo
      Sleeve features photos of band members in pharaonic costume. Jacket excerpt reads, "Variously attributing his moniker to his inability to play more than five chords on the organ, his stage clowning, or the bizarre premise of he and his down-home Pharoahs ("hey, these guys ain't real Arabs!"), Sam was actually Domingo Samudio of Dallas, Texas..."
    - Pharoahization! The best of Sam the Sham and the Pharaohs Santa Monica, CA: Rhino Records., 1965; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Creator: Sam the Sham and the Pharaohs (Musical Group)
    - Port Said: music of the Middle East New York, NY: Audio Fidelity., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Cover is a photo of Nejla Ates, dancing star of "Fanny". Jacket excerpt reads, "There are dancing girls who will perform their ancient ritual for a few modest coins (and for little more will take you into their tent for more enjoyable entertainment)".
    - Powerslave Hollywood, CA: Capitol., 1984; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Creator: Iron Maiden (Musical group)
      Cover features Iron Maiden mascot "Eddie the Head" posed variously as the sphinx and entombed as King Tut. Original paintings by Derek Riggs.
    - Pyramid New York, NY: Arista., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 15)
      Creator: Alan Parsons Project (Musical group)
      Excerpt from liner notes reads, "From the rise and fall of an ancient dynasty, to the quest for a key to unlock the secrets of the ancient universe..." Cover design by Hipgnosis.
    - Rides, rapes and rescues: themes from the great silent films Los Angeles, CA: Liberty., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Creator: Hennessey, Hangnails
      Cover features a series of photographs of Rudolph Valentino as the Sheik.
    - Rides, rapes and rescues: themes from the great silent films Los Angeles, CA: Liberty., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Creator: Brubeck, Wingy
    - Rides, rapes and rescues: themes from the great silent films Los Angeles, CA: Liberty., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Creator: Brandt, Carl
    - Robe New York, NY: Decca., 1954; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Robe New York, NY: Decca., 1954; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Robe New York, NY: Decca., 1954; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Creator: Hollywood Symphony Orchestra
    - Rock the casbah New York, NY: Epic., 1982; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 18)
      Creator: Clash (Musical group)
      Cover illustration features an Arab and a Hasidic Jew dancing in front of a mosque.
    - Salad days revival London cast London, England: That's Entertainment Records., 1982; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 19)
      Creator: Slade, Julian
      Back cover features a photo of Sheila Steafel in the role of "Asphynxia," dressed as Cleopatra.
    - Samson and Delilah New York, NY: Decca., 1950; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 10 inches (Box 4, Folder 20)
      Creator: Young, Victor, 1900-1956
      Cover is a photograph of Victor Mature and Hedy Lamarr as Samson and Delilah.
    - Samson and Delilah New York, NY: Decca., 1950; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 10 inches (Box 4, Folder 20)
      Creator: Victor Young Orchestra
    - Scheherazade New York, NY: London Records., 1961; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 21)
      Creator: Ansermet, Ernest
      Cover is a reproduction of a Persian miniature.
    - Scheherazade New York, NY: London Records., 1961; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 21)
      Creator: L'Orchestre de la Suisse Romande
    - Scheherazade New York, NY: London Records., 1961; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Scheherazade New York, NY: Vox Productions (Moss Music Group)., 1963; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Creator: Bamberg Symphony
    - Scheherazade New York, NY: Vox Productions (Moss Music Group)., 1963; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Creator: Perlea, Jonel
    - Scheherazade New York, NY: Vox Productions (Moss Music Group)., 1963; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Scheherazade New York, NY: RCA., 1972; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 23)
      Creator: Boston Pops
      Cover photograph features a woman dressed as Scheherazade.
    - Scheherazade New York, NY: RCA., 1972; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 23)
      Creator: Reiner, Fritz, 1888-1963
    - Scheherazade New York, NY: RCA., 1972; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 23)
      Creator: Chicago Symphony
    - Scheherazade New York, NY: RCA., 1972; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 23)
      Creator: Fiedler, Arthur, 1894-1979.
    - Scheherazade New York, NY: RCA., 1972; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 23)
      Creator: Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937
    - Scheherazade Deutsche Grammophon., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 24)
      Cover is a series of Persian miniatures.
    - Scheherazade Deutsche Grammophon., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 24)
      Creator: Berliner Philharmoniker
    - Scheherazade Deutsche Grammophon., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Scheherazade Russian Easter overture Chicago, IL: Mercury., 1963; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Scheherazade Russian Easter overture Chicago, IL: Mercury., 1963; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 25)
      Creator: Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra
    - Scheherazade Russian Easter overture Chicago, IL: Mercury., 1963; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 25)
      Creator: Dorati, Antal
    - Scheherazade Russian Easter overture Chicago, IL: Mercury., 1963; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Scheherazade capriccio espagnole London: Decca., 1984; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 26)
      Creator: Orchestre Symphonique de Montreal
      Cover illustration by Jean-Paul Veret-Lemarinier.
    - Scheherazade capriccio espagnole London: Decca., 1984; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Scheherazade capriccio espagnole London: Decca., 1984; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 26)
      Creator: Dutoit, Charles
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Chicago, IL: Mercury., 1952; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 27)
      Cover is a photograph of a woman dressed as Scheherazade.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Chicago, IL: Mercury., 1952; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Chicago, IL: Mercury., 1952; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Westminster., 1953; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 28)
      Creator: Quadri, Argeo
      Cover painting of King Shahryar and Scheherazade by Rado.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Westminster., 1953; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Westminster., 1953; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 28)
      Creator: Rado
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Westminster., 1953; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 28)
      Creator: Orchestra of the Vienna State Opera
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: RCA Victor., 1956; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 29)
      Creator: Martin Gould Orchestra
      Cover is a photograph of a woman dressed as Scheherezade.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: RCA Victor., 1956; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 29)
      Creator: Gould, Martin
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: RCA Victor., 1956; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: RCA., 1957; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 30)
      Cover is a photograph of a group of women dressed as harem girls.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: RCA., 1957; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Angel., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Cover painting by Serov.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Angel., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Creator: Serov
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Angel., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Angel., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Creator: Beecham, Thomas
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Camden, NJ: RCA Victor., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 32)
      Cover is a photo of a woman dressed as Scheherazade.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Camden, NJ: RCA Victor., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Camden, NJ: RCA Victor., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 4, Folder 32)
      Creator: Monteux, Pierre
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Camden, NJ: RCA Victor., 1960; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Creator: Chicago Symphony Orchestra
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Camden, NJ: RCA Victor., 1960; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Creator: Reiner, Fritz
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Camden, NJ: RCA Victor., 1960; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Creator: Philadelphia Orchestra
      Cover features a photo of a woman looking through a mashrabiyya.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Creator: Ormandy, Eugene
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Cover photo is a bejeweled woman looking through a mashrabiyya.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Camden, NJ: RCA., 1963; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Camden, NJ: RCA., 1963; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Camden, NJ: RCA., 1963; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Vanguard Stereolab., 1965; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Vanguard Stereolab., 1965; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Creator: Rossi, Mario
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Vanguard Stereolab., 1965; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hamburg, Germany: RCA., 1968; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hamburg, Germany: RCA., 1968; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hamburg, Germany: RCA., 1968; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Dunhill (ABC Records)., 1970; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Dunhill (ABC Records)., 1970; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Dunhill (ABC Records)., 1970; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: RCA., 1973; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Cover is a photo of a European woman dressed as Scheherazade.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: RCA., 1973; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: RCA., 1973; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1973; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Creator: Bernstein, Leonard
      Cover design by John Berg and Hiroshi Morishima.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1973; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Creator: New York Philharmonic
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Columbia., 1973; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hollywood, CA: Angel EMI., 1974; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Creator: Chagall, Marc
      Cover features a painting by Marc Chagall, "created especially for his friend, Conductor Mstislav Rostropovich, to illustrate this performance."
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hollywood, CA: Angel EMI., 1974; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hollywood, CA: Angel EMI., 1974; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Creator: Rostropovich, Mstislav
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hollywood, CA: Angel EMI., 1974; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Creator: Orchestre de Paris
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 London: Decca., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Recorded April 1974 in Royce Hall, University of California, Los Angeles. Cover art by Palladini.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 London: Decca., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Vox Productions (Moss Music Group)., 1976; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 13)
      Creator: Semkow, Jerzy
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Vox Productions (Moss Music Group)., 1976; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 13)
      Creator: Saint Louis Symphony Orchestra
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Vox Productions (Moss Music Group)., 1976; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: London., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 14)
      Creator: Maazel, Lorin
      Cover is an illustration of Scheherazade at King Shahryar's feet.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: London., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 14)
      Creator: Cleveland Orchestra
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: London., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 West Germany: Deutsche Grammophon., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Creator: Boston Symphony Orchestra
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 West Germany: Deutsche Grammophon., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 West Germany: Deutsche Grammophon., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Creator: Ozawa, Seiji
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: RCA., 1979; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 16)
      Cover photograph by Patrice Casanova. Art direction by Helene Guetary.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: RCA., 1979; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: RCA., 1979; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Los Angeles, CA: Chalfont Records., 1979; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Cover painting by Steve Garst is entitled, "The Ship Goes to Pieces on a Rock Surmounted by a Bronze Warrior."
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Los Angeles, CA: Chalfont Records., 1979; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Creator: Tjeknavorian, Loris
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Los Angeles, CA: Chalfont Records., 1979; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hollywood, CA: EMI., 1979; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Cover photo of Nijinsky as Scheherazade, designed by P. Iribe. Jacket excerpt reads, "Baghdad is the focal point around which "The Arabian Nights" stories of India, China, Persia and Arabia revolve."
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hollywood, CA: EMI., 1979; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hollywood, CA: EMI., 1979; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Creator: Svetlanov, Yevgeny
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hayes, Middlesex, England: EMI., 1983; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 19)
      Cover is an illustration of Scheherazade, by Dick Elescas.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hayes, Middlesex, England: EMI., 1983; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hayes, Middlesex, England: EMI., 1983; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 19)
      Creator: Muti, Riccardo
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hayes, Middlesex, England: EMI., 1983; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 19)
      Creator: Elescas, Dick
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hollywood, CA: Angel (Capitol Records)., 1985; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Cover painting is "Scene in a Moslem Cemetery: A Man Leading a Woman by the Hand" by Edmund Dulac.
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hollywood, CA: Angel (Capitol Records)., 1985; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 Hollywood, CA: Angel (Capitol Records)., 1985; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Epic., ca. 1950s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 21)
      Creator: Concertgebouw Orchestra of Amsterdam
      Cover photograph by Hal Reiff. Jacket excerpt reads, "As the Arabian Nights have come down to us in the West, they are Moslem in spirit..."
    - Scheherazade, opus 35 New York, NY: Epic., ca. 1950s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 21)
      Creator: Beinum, Edward Van